To activate or deactivate an object
オブジェクトをスクリプトによって
via scripting you can use the
有効化または無効化するには
SetActive function.
SetActive 関数を使用します。
This will switch your object on or off
これによりオブジェクトをオンまたはオフに切り替えて
in terms of it being active in the scene.
シーン上でアクティブかどうかを変更します。
In this example we have a simple Start
このサンプルでは Start 関数があり
function that contains
gameObject.SetActive(false) が
gameObject.SetActive(false).
含まれています。
And you can see that my gameobject
さらに現在ゲームオブジェクトが
is currently active.
アクティブであることを確認出来ます。
If I press play, the object is deactivated.
もしゲーム再生をするとオブジェクトは無効化されます。
However when working with hierarchies of
しかしながらオブジェクトの階層で作業をするときは
objects, it's important to know that
親オブジェクトを無効化できることを
a parent object can be deactivated,
覚えておくべきです。
which will stop a child object being active
これによって子オブジェクトがシーン上で
in the scene. However it will remain active
アクティブではなくなります。しかしながら
within it's hierarchy.
Hierarchy の中でアクティブであり続けます。
This is so that you can disable individual
これは個別のオブジェクトを無効化しつつ
objects but maintain control over groups
親オブジェクトを使用して
of them using the parent object.
グループに対する制御を維持できるようにするためです。
You can see here that if I select the Physics
っここでは prop_physicsDoor を選択して
door and select the child Door Object
子オブジェクトである prop_physicsDoor_door を選択して
and deactivate it in the inspector
インスペクタ上で無効化すれば
it becomes deselected, the icon is greyed
非選択状態となり、アイコンがグレーアウトされて
out and I've unchecked the box next to it's name.
さらに名前の隣にあるボックスもチェックがオフとしてあります。
However if I deactivate the parent object
しかし親オブジェクトを子オブジェクトの代わりに
instead of the child you can see that I've
無効化すれば
deactivated all of the child objects but
全ての子オブジェクトを無効化したけれども
it remains active within the hierarchy,
Hierarchy の中でアクティブのままであり、
as does the other child object, the frame.
子オブジェクトである prop_physicsDoor_frame も同様です。
To check if an object is active within
オブジェクトがシーンの中または
the scene or in a hierarchy,
Hierarchy ビューでアクティブであるか確認するためには
you can query using the using the
activeSelf および activeInHierarchy ステートを使用して
activeSelf and activeInHierarchy states.
クエリをかけることが出来ます。
In this 'check states' script I have a public
この CheckState スクリプトの中では
variable for a gameobject and I'm checking
ゲームオブジェクトのための public 変数があり、
that gameobject as to whether it's
そのゲームオブジェクトが
active self or active in the Hierarchy.
activeSelf であるか、activeInHierarchy であるか確認できます。
We're referring to the physics door we
ここでは 前述の prop_physicsDoor を示していて
mentioned previously and debug logging
それらのステートを Debug.Log により
the state of those to the console.
コンソール出力しています。
So when I press play
ここでゲーム再生すると
the door itself is active
ドアそのものが有効化され
and the hierarchy that it's in is
中にある Hierarchy もまた有効化されます。
also active. However, if I deactivate the
しかし、親オブジェクトを無効化して
parent and press play again,
ゲーム再生すると、
the door itself is active but the hierarchy
ドアそのものは有効化されますが、ドアが含まれる Hierarchy は
that it's in is not active
無効となります。
because the parent is deactivated,
これは親オブジェクトが無効化されたためであり
and is therefore not active in the scene.
結果としてシーンでは有効でないためです。
It should also be noted that when a child
さらに親オブジェクトが無効であるために、
object is inactive because it's
子オブジェクトが無効である場合、
parent is inactive using setActive
setActive を true に変更しても
to true will not make that child object
子オブジェクトは
active. It can only become active again
有効になりません。有効となるのは
once it's parent is made active.
親オブジェクトが有効となる時です。 (翻訳:gamesonytablet)